我们能在这座城市生活很幸运 他们说战争很恐怖
We're lucky to be in The City. They say the war was terrible.
除此以外的世界 早已被战争摧毁
That the rest of the world was destroyed.
我们城市的缔造者建起高墙 保护我们的安全
Our founders built the wall to keep us safe
他们为了维持和平 把我们
and they divided us into five groups,
分成了五类 五个派别
factions, to keep the peace.
那些拥有知识和逻辑分析能力的聪明人
The smart ones, the ones who value knowledge and logic
属于智慧派
are in Erudite.
他们无所不知
They know everything.
和平派的人务农
Amity farm the land.
他们永远温静而和谐 总是那么快乐
They're all about kindness and harmony, always happy.
诚实派的特质是诚实和守序
Candor value honesty and order.
他们只说真话 即使有时候你希望他们别那么诚实
They tell the truth, even when you wish they wouldn't.
然后是无畏派
And then there's Dauntless.
他们是我们的保护者 我们的战士 我们的警察
They're our protectors, our soldiers, our police.
我一直都觉得他们帅呆了
I always thought they were amazing.
勇敢 无畏 而且自由
Brave, fearless and free.
有人觉得无畏派的成员都是疯子
Some people think Dauntless are crazy,
事实上 确实有一点
which they kind of are.
来 比阿特丽斯
Come on, Beatrice.
我是无私派的人
My faction is Abnegation.
别人都叫我们"呆子"
The others all call us "stiffs."
我们过着简单的生活
We lead a simple life,
无私地奉献自己以帮助他人
selfless, dedicated to helping others.
我们甚至给那些无派别的人食物
We even feed the Factionless,
他们不属于任何派别
the ones who don't fit in anywhere.
因为我们是人民公仆
Because we're public servants,
人们信任我们 让我们执掌政府
we're trusted to run the government.
我父亲和城市的领导人马库斯一起工作
My father works alongside our leader, Marcus.
一切都井然有序 每个人都知道自己的归属
It all works. Everyone knows where they belong.
除了我
Except for me.
母亲说 有一种艺术叫做忘我
My mother says there's an art to losing yourself.
但我还没学会怎么做
But I haven't figured it out yet.
我应当永远摒除私心
I'm supposed to never think of myself,
永远致力于帮助他人
to always help others.
别对着镜子看太久
To never look too long in the mirror.
你紧张吗?
Are you nervous?
不紧张
No.
你当时呢? 你测试前紧张吗?
Were you? For your test?
唔 不紧张
Mmm-mm. No.
只是吓坏了
I was terrified.
但是当时我没必要紧张的 你也是
But I didn't have any reason to be and neither do you.
准备好了
That's all you get.
规矩必须遵守
Rules are rules.
今天我要去参加测试
Today I take the test.
我很害怕测试结果显示我不属于无私派
I'm scared it'll tell me I'm not Abnegation.
那样 我就不得不离开我的家人
That I have to leave my family.
但我更怕测试结果是让我留在这里
But I'm even more scared that it will tell me to stay.
对于我哥哥伽勒 这事儿就简单多了
For my brother Caleb, it's easy.
让我来帮您吧
Let me help you with that.
他天生就乐于助人
He's a natural.
比阿特丽斯 能不能帮忙拿下那些袋子?
Beatrice, do you want to get the other bags?
抱歉
Sorry.
如果她双目失明或者残疾呢? 你会不会帮助她?
What if she'd been blind or an amputee? Would you have helped her then?
- 我想过帮助她的  - 没有那么难的
- I was thinking about helping her.  - It's not that hard.
对你可能不难
For you, maybe.
放松 比阿特丽斯 深呼吸然后相信测试
Just relax, Beatrice. Take a deep breath and trust the test.
相信测试
Trust the test.
测试会告诉我我是谁 属于哪里
Test will tell me who I am, where I belong.
我聪明吗?
Am I smart?
仁慈吗? 我是否诚实?
Kind? Am I honest?
无私? 还是勇敢?
Selfless? Or brave?
嘿 那些没给我们的食物
Hey. So, all the food that we're not getting,
你们都拿去给那些无派别人士了?
you guys are giving away to the Factionless?
- 是吗?  - 是
- Right? Yeah?  - Yeah.
你这个骗子 为什么你要说谎?
You're a liar. Why are you lying to me?
大家都知道你们把它们扣下来私藏了
Everybody knows you keep it for yourselves.
你为什么不承认? 嗯?
So why don't you just admit it? Huh?
我跟你说话呢 你们这些呆子是都聋了还是怎么着? 嘿!
I'm talking to you. Are all you stiffs deaf or something? Hey!
比阿特丽斯...
Beatrice...
别去
Don't.
一百年前 战争结束后
One hundred years ago, after the war,
我们的祖先创造了一个他们认为
our founders created a system they believed
足以阻止未来的战争并创造恒久和平的系统
would prevent future conflict and create lasting peace.
今天 以人格测试为目的的能力测试
Today, aptitude testing based on your personality
将把你们分进其中一个派别
will assign you to one of the factions.
尽管我们认为 你们根据测试结果
While it is our belief that choosing the faction
来选择相应的派别可以保障你们在这个派别取得成就
indicated by your test is the best way to ensure success within the faction system,
但在明天的仪式上 无论测试结果如何
it is your right tomorrow at the choosing ceremony
要选择五派中的哪个派别的权利掌握在你们自己手里
to choose any of the five factions, regardless of your test results.
然而 你们的决定一旦做出便不可更改
However, once the choice has been made, there will be no change permitted.
你们无私派是怎么看待镜子的?
What is it with you Abnegation and mirrors?
我们拒绝虚伪的东西
We reject vanity.
是啊 我知道 坐下
Yeah. I know. Sit down.
我是托丽 负责给你做测试
I'm Tori. I'll be administering your test.
你会面临一系列的选择
You'll be offered a series of choices
来测试你对于每个派别的资质
to test your aptitude for each faction
直到得出一个结论
until you get one result.
不要紧张
I wouldn't sweat it.
大约95%的人都继承了父母的派别
95% get the faction of their origin,
而从你的面相上看...
and from the looks of you...
看出什么?
What is it?
喝干净
Bottoms up.
选一个
Choose.
现在就选 趁一切还来得及
Now. Before it's too late.
- 为什么? 选一个然后干嘛?  - 选一个
- Why? What will I do with them?  - Choose.
告诉我
Just tell me.
狗狗!
Puppy!
起来
Get up.
我们得在管理员来之前出去
We're going out the back door before a supervisor comes.
- 但是我的结果是什么?  - 快点!
- But what was my result?  - Come on!
发生了什么?
What happened?
你告诉你家里人 血清让你难受恶心
You're going to tell your family that the serum made you sick
- 所以我让你回家了 听明白了没?  - 没有 但是我的结果到底是什么?
- and that I sent you home. All right?  - No, but what was my result?
无私
Abnegation.
智慧和无畏
And Erudite. And Dauntless.
无畏...
Dauntless...
你的结果是不确定性的
Your results were inconclusive.
不可能 这太荒谬了
That's impossible. It doesn't make any sense.
不 不是不可能 只是极其罕见而已
No. Not impossible. It's just extremely rare.
他们把这类人叫做"分歧者"
They call it "Divergent."
你不能告诉任何人你的测试结果 甚至是你父母
You can't tell anyone about this. Not even your parents.
所有人都会认为
As far as the world is concerned,
你的测试结果是无私 因为我手动设定了这个结论
you received an Abnegation result because that is what I manually entered.
那我在选择仪式上应该怎么做?
So what am I supposed to do at the choosing ceremony?
我本来应该得知该怎么做的
I was supposed to learn what to do.
今天的测试应该告诉我我属于哪个派别
This was supposed to tell me what faction to choose, the test.
- 我们应该信任测试  - 测试对你无效
- We're supposed to trust the test.  - The test didn't work on you.
你得相信自己
You have to trust yourself.
你今儿怎么样?
What happened to you today?
测试结束后 你去哪儿啦?
Where did you go after your test?
我觉得有点恶心 所以他们就先让我回来了
I got sick, so they sent me home early.
你完成测试了吗?
Did you finish your test?
嗯
Mmm-hmm.
你的结果是什么?
What was your result?
你的呢?
What was yours?
你为什么不打一声招呼就走了?
Why did you just leave without telling anybody?
我不舒服
I was sick.
比阿特丽斯...
Beatrice...
我觉得你根本不了解我们现在面临多危急的状况
I don't think you understand the level of scrutiny we're under.
他们正想尽办法地败坏我们的名声
They're doing everything they can to discredit us right now.
谁?
Who is?
智慧派
Erudite.
他们觉得我们不配执掌政府 他们才是政府的主人
They believe that they should be the governing faction, not us.
所以你们现在要小心点 知道吗?
So you have to be careful right now, okay?
即使马库斯也遭到攻击
Even Marcus is under attack.
为什么?
For what?
那是一桩旧案了
It's an old accusation.
他虐待他的儿子
That he mistreated his son
然后他儿子叛逃了
and that's why the boy defected.
- 事实真如此吗?  - 不
- Is that true?  - No.
当然不是
Course not.
孩子天生叛逆
Children defect for all kinds of reasons.
别在这儿耽搁太久了 你们需要好好睡一觉...
Don't take too long in here. You need a good night's sleep...
为了明天的典礼
For tomorrow.
我 唔...
I, um...
我们爱你们
We love you.
晚安
Good night.
我为你骄傲 亲爱的
I'm so proud of you, honey.
- 比阿特丽斯?  - 怎么?
- Beatrice?  - What?
明天选择的时候...
Tomorrow when we choose...
你要好好为家人考虑一下
You have to think of the family.
嗯
Yeah.
但你也要为自己考虑
But you also have to think of yourself.
各派成员们 请在指定区域就座
Factions, please gather in your assigned areas.
早安 珍宁
Morning, Jeanine.
早 安德鲁 马库斯最近怎么样?
Good morning, Andrew. How is Marcus holding up?
一切正常
As well as can be expected.
我们要找到散播谣言的人
We need to find out who's behind these rumors.
我觉得 我们都知道是谁在捣鬼
I think we all know who it is.
如果是智慧派的人 我发誓我一定会把他找出来
If it's someone from Erudite, I promise I'll find out who.
这是你的孩子们啊 我都不知道他们也要今天选择呢
These are your children. I don't think I knew they were choosing today.
- 你叫什么?  - 我是... 我是伽勒
- What's your name?  - I'm... I'm Caleb.
- 很高兴认识您  - 我叫珍宁·马修斯
- It's a pleasure to meet you.  - Jeanine Matthews.
你叫?
And you are?
这是比阿特丽斯
This is Beatrice.
你们俩今天都要做出重要的决定
Well, you both have a big decision to make today.
我相信 无论你们选择什么 你们的父母都会支持的
I'm sure your parents will support whatever choice you make.
这不应该是选择的
That's not supposed to be a choice.
测试应该告诉我们我们要做什么
The test should tell us what to do.
- 你仍有权利自己选择  - 但你们不希望我们那么做
- You're still free to choose.  - But you don't really want that.
比阿特丽斯...
Beatrice...
我希望你正视自己的内心 选择你真正归属的派别
I want you to choose who you truly are and where you truly belong.
不能因为一时兴起 也不能因为你希望成为某个人而做出选择
Not on a whim. Not because you wish you were someone you're not.
而应当因为你非常了解自己
But because you honestly know yourself.
我希望你做出明智的选择 而且我知道你会的
I want you to choose wisely. And I know you will.
派别的系统是就像一个生命体
The faction system is a living being
你们都是其中的细胞
composed of cells, all of you.
这个生命体能够存活且繁荣的唯一方式
And the only way it can survive and thrive
就是每一个人都找到自己最准确的位置
is for each of you to claim your rightful place.
未来属于那些知道他们归宿的人
The future belongs to those who know where they belong.
在离开这个房间之后
When we leave this room,
你们将不再是家庭的从属者
you will no longer be dependents
而是社会中的正式成员
but full-fledged members of our society.
派别比亲情重要
Faction before blood.
我爱你...
I love you...
不论你的选择是什么
No matter what.
乔纳森·齐格勒
Jonathan Ziegler.
智慧派
Erudite.
杰弗里·耶茨
Jeffrey Yates.
无畏派
Dauntless.
摩根·斯托克斯
Morgan Stokes.
和平派
Amity.
- 克莱尔·赛纯  - 诚实
- Claire Satron.  - Candor.
- 山姆·罗伯森  - 无私派
- Sam Robertson.  - Abnegation.
伽勒·普莱尔
Caleb Prior.
智慧派
Erudite.
请安静
Quiet, please.
比阿特丽斯·普莱尔
Beatrice Prior.
无畏派
Dauntless.
欢迎加入无畏派!
Welcome to Dauntless!
快点!咱们走!
Come on! Let's go!
走!
Come on!
抱歉
Sorry.
你做到了
You made it.
- 我是克里斯汀娜  - 我是比阿特丽斯
- I'm Christina.  - Beatrice.
他们是真要弄死我们 还是只有我有这种感觉?
Is it just me or are they trying to kill us?
准备!
Get ready!
哇!
Yeah!
- 他们在跳  - 啥?
- They're jumping.  - What?
如果不跳呢?
What if you don't jump?
你觉得呢? 你会变成无家可归的人
What do you think? You'll be factionless.
好运啦 阿尔
Good luck, Al.
哇哦!
Whoa!
- 一起跳?  - 嗯
- Together?  - Yeah.
一 二 三...
One, two, three...
好啦 都听我说!
All right, listen up!
我是埃里克 领导之一
I'm Eric. I'm one of your leaders.
如果你们想加入无畏派 这是入门考核
If you want to enter Dauntless, this is the way in.
可你要是连跳下去的勇气都没有
And if you don't have the guts to jump,
那你便不属于无畏派
then you don't belong in Dauntless.
下面有水还是怎么?
Is there water at the bottom or something?
跳下去不就知道了
I guess you'll find out.
或者不跳也行
Or not.
咱们刚跳了一次 还要跳一次?
We just jumped. They want us to jump again?
总得有出头鸟吧 谁第一个?
Someone's gotta go first. Who's it gonna be?
我
Me.
脱吧 呆子!
Yeah, stiff, take it off!
再穿上!
Put it back on!
今天 新生训练
Today, Initiate.
怎么 有人把你推下来的?
What, you get pushed?
不是
No.
你叫什么?
What's your name?
叫...
It's...
有那么难记吗?
Is that a hard one?
要是想换个名字 就换吧 但得想好
You can pick a new one if you want, but make it good.
过了这村就没这店了
You don't get to pick again.
好... 我叫特丽丝
Okay... My name's Tris.
第一个跳下来的 特丽丝!
First jumper, Tris!
欢迎来到无畏派
Welcome to Dauntless.
出身无畏派家庭的 跟着劳伦 其余人跟着我
Dauntless-born, go with Lauren, transfers stay with me.
去吧
Go.
这边走
This way.
我一般在控制室工作
Most of the time I work in Intelligence,
但训练期间 我是你们的导师
but during your training, I'll be your instructor.
我叫阿四
My name's Four.
那个数字四吗?
Four like the number?
没错
Exactly like the number.
怎么说 一到三都被别人占了?
What happened, one through three were taken?
你叫什么?
What's your name?
克里斯汀娜
Christina.
好 克里斯汀娜
Well, Christina.
我教你的第一堂课就是
The first lesson you learn from me
在这要是想活命
if you wanna survive here,
就把嘴给我闭好
is keep your mouth shut.
听明白没?
Do you understand me?
明白
Yes.
很好
Good.
跟我来
Follow me.
这就是基地深坑
This is The Pit.
无畏派的中枢
The center of life here at Dauntless.
你们接下来十周时间要住在这
You're gonna be sleeping here for the next 10 weeks.
男的还是女的?
Girls or boys?
都住这
Both.
- 棒  - 这就对了嘛
- Nice.  - That works.
这就算棒的话 那浴室就更合你们胃口了
If you like this, you're gonna love the bathroom.
太赞了
Great.
好吧...
Okay...
- 开玩笑?  - 就没有别的地方了?
- Seriously?  - Is there no other area?
开玩笑吧?
Are you kidding?
别拘谨 就像在家一样 诚实派
You should feel right at home, Candor.
没必要遮遮掩掩
Everything out in the open.
这是开玩笑吧?
Is this a joke?
换衣服
Get changed.
好 有人要冲澡吗?
Right. Shower, anyone?
美腿啊 呆子
Nice legs, stiff.
- 嗨  - 怎么样?
- Hey.  - How you doin'?
我们能坐那儿吗?
Shall we sit there?
你以前从没见过汉堡吗?
Have you never seen a hamburger before?
见是见过 但从没吃过
No, I've seen one. I just have never eaten one.
无私派只吃粗茶淡饭
Abnegation eat plain food.
主要吃素 不放酱料 尽量少烹调
Plant-based diet with no sauces and a minimum of seasoning.
你这啃的是哪本课本?
Which textbook did you swallow?
也很高兴认识你 我叫威尔 来自智慧派
Nice to meet you, too. I'm Will. Erudite.
看出来了
Of course you are.
无意冒犯 但我还以为无私派连饭都不吃呢
No offense, but I'm surprised Abnegation even eats at all.
太自私了 不是吗? 怪不得你离开了
Too selfish, right? No wonder you left.
要想和诚实派做朋友 得很自信才行
You gotta be pretty self-confident to be friends with a Candor.
这是什么意思?
What is that supposed to mean?
你们口无遮拦 想到什么说什么
You have no filter. You say the first thing that comes into your head.
比方说 "你是个白痴"?
You mean like, "You're an idiot"?
说得好 阿尔 至少我们说了实话
Nice one, Al. At least we tell the truth.
智慧派说实话是因为我们掌握了事实
Erudite can tell the truth because we have the facts.
别再提你们的老派别了
I don't want to hear about your old factions.
你们现在都是无畏派
You're Dauntless now.
你也是转派的? 还是生于无畏派家庭?
Were you a transfer, too? Or Dauntless-born?
你在开玩笑?
Are you kidding?
没有
No.
你凭什么认为有资格和我说话?
What makes you think you can talk to me?
这...
It...
一定是因为你看起来太和蔼可亲了
Must be because you're so approachable.
小心点
Careful.
阿四...
Four...
朋友啊 你可真是活得不耐烦了
You, my friend, have a death wish.
他是班上的第一名
You know, he was first in his class.
他们两次想招他进领导层 但他都拒绝了
They tried to recruit him for leadership twice, but he said no.
新生 起立
Initiates, stand.
你们选择加入了勇士一派
You have chosen to join the warrior faction
肩负保卫这座城市及其居民的责任
tasked with the defense of this city and all its inhabitants.
我们信仰正当的勇敢行为
We believe in ordinary acts of bravery
以及促使人们
and the courage that drives one person
拔刀相助的勇气
to stand up for another.
铭记于心
Respect that.
让我们为你自豪
Do us proud.
哇!
Whoa!
所有人两分钟内到基地深坑集合
I want everyone in The Pit. Two minutes.
训练分两个阶段
There are two stages of training.
第一个是体力
The first is physical.
将体能逼到极限
Push your bodies to the breaking point
便能掌握格斗技巧
and you'll master the methods of combat.
第二个是意志力 同样 逼到极限
The second is mental. Again, breaking point.
你们将直面自己最深的恐惧 在被打倒之前战胜恐惧
You'll face your worst fears and conquer them unless they get you first.
你们将与无畏派出身者分开训练
You'll be trained separately from the Dauntless-born,
但放在一起排名
but you'll be ranked together.
新生训练之后 排名会决定你们去做什么工作
After initiations, rankings will determine what jobs you move into.
领导层 守护围栏 或是防止无派别人士自相残杀
Leadership, guarding the fence, or keeping the Factionless from killing each other.
排名也会决定谁出局
The rankings will also determine who gets cut.
出局?
Cut?
每一训练阶段结束后 排名最末的新生将离开这里
At the end of each stage of training, the lowest-ranking Initiates will be leaving us.
去干什么?
To do what?
回家是不可能了 只能成为无派别人士
There's no going home to your families, so you'd live factionless.
- 为什么事先没有声明?  - 新规矩
- Why didn't we know that?  - It's a new rule.
新规矩? 理应事先告知才对
A new rule? Somebody should have told us that.
为什么? 那样你就不来这里了吗?
Why? Would you have chosen differently?
因为恐惧?
Out of fear?
如果真是这样 那你现在就可以出局了
I mean, if that's the case, you might as well get out now.
如果你真的属于我们 那成败与否根本无足轻重
If you're really one of us, it won't matter to you that you might fail.
你们选择了我们
Now you chose us.
现在轮到我们来选择你们了
Now we get to choose you.
就是按统计学来看 你到现在也该打中一次靶子了
Statistically speaking, you should have hit the target at least once by now.
哪怕是瞎猫碰上死耗子
Even by accident.
嗨 有什么情况吗?
Hey. What have you got?
无派别人士 没什么动作
Factionless. Not doing anything.
瞧瞧 呆子 那就是你的新家庭
Check it out, stiff. That's gonna be your new family.
快去打个招呼
Go say "Hi."
准备好真正干上一架了吗?
You ready for some real fighting?
差得远呢
Not even close.
第一个跳下来的那个!
First jumper!
上格斗场
In the ring.
最后一个跳下来的!
Last jumper!
来干一架吧
Time to fight.
要打多久?
How long do we fight for?
直到一方不能接着打
Till one of you can't continue.
或者某一方认输
Or one of you concedes.
这是老规矩
According to the old rules.
新规矩是 不准认输
New rules, no one concedes.
你真想让她们第一次上场就往死里打啊?
You really want to lose 'em on their first fight?
真正的勇士绝不认输
A brave man never surrenders.
你说得轻松 咱们那个时候规则可不是这样
Lucky for you, those weren't the rules when we fought.
这一项要打分 所以卖力打
You'll be scored on this, so fight hard.
开始!
Go!
别害怕 呆子!
Don't be scared, stiff!
漂亮 特丽丝!
Nice, Tris!
- 漂亮  - 好!
- Nice.  - Yeah!
大家过来
All right, guys, over here.
听好了
Listen up.
知道这板是干什么的吗?
Know what this board is?
这是你们的命
It's your life.
我们每天为你们打分排名
We grade you every day.
要是第一阶段结束你们的名字还是红色 那就出局了
If you're still in the red by the end of the first stage, you're out.
我不可能通过的
I'm never gonna make it.
肯定可以
Yes, you are.
我是这里最弱的一个
I'm the weakest one here.
那你将是进步最大的那个
Then you'll be most improved.
你可是诚实派 不该撒谎的
You're Candor. You're not supposed to lie.
我以前是诚实派 再说我也没有撒谎
I was Candor. And I'm not lying.
他们要是把我踢出局的话 我爸妈应该会接我回去
If they cut me, I think my parents would take me back.
不是那样的
No, it doesn't work like that.
就算他们想 他们的派别也不允许
Even if they wanted to, their faction wouldn't allow it.
就算我父母接我回去
Even if my parents would take me back,
我也不再属于那里了
I wouldn't belong there anymore.
- 有点压抑啊  - 是
- This is getting depressing.  - Yeah.
你知道我们该干嘛吗? 去纹身
You know what we should do? Get tattoos.
你知道吗 可以纹自己的脸?
Did you know they had a tattoo of your face?
- 喜欢吗?  - 嗯
- Like it?  - Yeah.
- 想纹在哪?  - 不知道
- Where would you get it?  - I don't know.
有什么建议吗?
Where do you suggest?
哪里都行
Anywhere you want.
这里吧 是这样的
Here, it's this thing here.
你还记得我吧?
You remember me, right?
- 我只是在想你能不能...  - 不
- I was just wondering if you could...  - No.
我只负责纹身
I just do tattoos.
好吧
Okay.
我要纹这个
I'd like this one.
谢谢了
Please.
我能不能问问你...
Can I just ask you...
你不该选无畏派的
You made a mistake choosing Dauntless.
- 他们会发现你的...  - 谁?
- They'll find out about you...  - Who?
谁会发现?
Who will?
那些你对其构成威胁的人
The people you're a threat to.
- 什么人? 谁 无畏派?  - 不 整个社会
- What people? Who, Dauntless?  - No, society.
你如果不属于任何一类 他们就无法控制你
If you don't fit into a category, they can't control you.
我不明白
I don't get it.
我是无畏派 我要进无畏派 我选择了无畏派
I'm Dauntless. I'm going to be Dauntless. I chose Dauntless.
为了你 希望如此
For your sake, I hope so.
你身体太弱 没有肌肉
You're weak. You have no muscle.
- 你这样是没法赢的  - 多谢提醒
- You're never gonna win, not like that.  - That's good to know.
你得利用你的全身
Yeah, you're gonna have to use your whole body.
这里绷紧
Keep tension here.
- 好的...  - 然后开攻
- Okay...  - And go on offense.
你有速度 因此可以先发制人
You're fast, so you could win if you attack first.
一旦突破防守 便直捣喉咙
You get inside, you jab to the throat.
阿四!
Four!
接着练
Keep working.
对不起了 威尔
Sorry about that, Will.
加油啊 克丽丝
Come on, Chris.
住手... 住手!
Stop... Stop!
够了 我不行了
I'm done. I'm done.
你要住手?
You need to stop?
好
Okay.
我来帮你
Let me give you a hand.
谢谢
Thanks.
好了 大家都休息一下!
All right, let's everyone take a break!
感觉好点了没?
You feelin' a little better?
好多了
Yeah, I'm fine.
哇!
Whoa!
抓住铁栏
Grab the rail.
松手亦可
Or don't.
给你三个选择
You've got three options.
在那儿吊着 我就不计你的懦弱
Hang there and I'll forget your cowardice.
掉下去摔死
Fall and die.
或者放弃
Or give up.
但如果放弃 就出局了
But if you give up, you're out.
加油啊 克丽丝!
Come on, Chris!
够了!
Time!
无畏派从不言败
Dauntless never give up.
作为无畏派 我们为界内的每一条生命战斗 不能失败
As Dauntless, we fight to protect every life inside the fence, without fail.
这就是这样训练你们的原因
That's why we train you the way we do.
教你们永不言弃
To teach you not to give up.
并找出谁能胜任
And to find out who has what it takes.
即使已沉静多年 也可能随时发生变化
Even though it's been quiet out there for years, that could change at any moment.
所以我们必须做好一切准备
So we have to be ready for everything.
喔!
Whoo!
外面那些是什么?
What's out there?
怪物们
Monsters.
和平派的农庄
Amity farms.
我知道 但比那更远的地方是什么?
No, I know. But beyond that?
战后一直荒废的地方
Places that never recovered from the war.
你知道吗?
Do you know?
只能说他们建围墙是有原因的
Let's just say they built their fence for a reason.
小子!
Man!
你还挺擅长这个啊
You're kinda good at this.
来吧
Come on.
真可悲
That was pathetic.
它打滑了
It slipped.
那去捡回来啊!
Well, go get it!
什么 他们还在扔的时候去捡?
What, while they're throwing?
你怕了吗?
Are you afraid?
怕被飞来的刀子刺伤? 确实
Of getting stabbed by an airborne knife? Yeah.
所有人停下来
Everybody stop.
站在靶子前面
Stand in front of the target.
阿四 借你的手一用
Four, gimme a hand here.
他扔刀子的时候 你就站在那里
You're gonna stand there while he throws those knives.
要是我看到你怕了 你就走人
And if I see you flinch, you're out.
今天你要学到的一点是
One thing you will learn here
命令是不可违抗的
is that orders are not optional.
住手
Stop.
谁都可以站在靶子前面 那并不能证明什么
Anyone can stand in front of a target. It doesn't prove anything.
那你可以代替他站在那里
Then it should be easy for you to take his place.
规则不变
Same rules apply.
哦 不是吧 阿四
Oh, come on, Four.
你可以扔得更近一点
You can get closer than that.
- 你想让我切她一点头发?  - 是 就切掉头顶的一点头发吧
- You want me to give her a little trim?  - Yeah, maybe just a little off the top.
对于勇敢 呆子
Points for bravery, stiff.
不是谁都能像你一样 有些人从此就张不开嘴了
Not as many as you just lost for opening your mouth.
现在自己小心点
Now watch yourself.
我们训练的是士兵 不是叛军
We train soldiers, not rebels.
今天到此为止 出去
But we're done for today. Get out.
- 你还好吗?  - 你切到我了
- You all right?  - You cut me.
我故意的
I meant to.
你故意的?
You meant to?
你以为不让你受点伤 他会放过你吗?
You think he was gonna let you off without a scratch?
要是我没切到你 你还站在那里呢
You'd still be standing there if I hadn't hit you.
这么说我该谢谢你了?
So am I supposed to thank you?
你应该学聪明点
You're supposed to be smart.
要是我想伤你 我就做得出来
If I wanted to hurt you, I would have.
她来了
There she is.
你真的是不想活了
You do have a death wish.
我想不到你会对埃里克说那种话
I can't believe you said that to Eric.
你是唯一站出来反对他的人
You're the only one who's ever stood up to him.
看看你的耳朵 我们帮你清理一下
Look at your ear. Let's get you cleaned up.
嘿 特丽丝 干得不错
Hey, Tris. That was cool.
谢谢
Thanks.
印象深刻啊 呆子 恭喜你
Impressive, stiff. Congrats.
闭嘴
Shut up.
怎么? 嘿 你现在出名了 跟埃里克没有关系
What? Hey, you're famous now. I mean, not because of the thing with Eric.
你上新闻了 真的 听着
You're in the news. Yeah, listen.
"最近的转入者安德鲁·普莱尔的孩子
"The recent transfers of Beatrice and Caleb Prior,
比阿特丽斯·普莱尔和伽勒·普莱尔
children of Andrew Prior, call into question the soundness
对无私派的教育和价值有所质疑
of Abnegation's teachings and values.
是什么让他们选择离开?
What prompted them to leave?
答案也许就在于整个派别腐败的理想
Perhaps the answer lies in the corrupted ideal of an entire faction.
盗窃资源 普遍无能
The theft of resources, the general incompetence,
虐待孩子"
the abuse of their children."
他们打你了吗 像马库斯·伊顿的孩子那样?
Did they beat you, like Marcus Eaton's kid?
他们没有打过人 他们是好人
They didn't beat anyone. They're good people.
好吧 所以你要离开?
Right. And that's why you left?
我说错什么了吗?
Was it something I said?
- 他是个笨蛋  - 没错
- He's an idiot.  - Yeah.
嗯 没关系
Yeah. That's okay.
她来无畏派做什么?
What's she doing at Dauntless?
普莱尔
Prior.
你是安德鲁·普莱尔的女儿 对吗?
You're Andrew Prior's daughter, aren't you?
比阿特丽斯
Beatrice.
这里只有特丽丝
It's just Tris now.
特丽丝 这名字我喜欢
Tris, I like that.
嗯
Hmm.
特丽丝 不管你父母怎么想 也不管你的测试结果是什么
You made an impressive choice, Tris, despite your parents.
你的选择令人钦佩
And your test result.
你看过我的测试结果了?
You've seen my test result?
当然
Of course.
我很高兴你非常聪明 了解自己的内心
I'm glad you were smart enough to know your own mind.
如果有什么需要可以来找我
Let me know if you ever need anything.
好奇怪啊
Well, that was weird.
是啊
Yeah.
你觉得发生什么事了?
What do you think is goin' on?
我猜他们在抓分歧者
I bet they're hunting Divergents.
智慧派的人整天都在聊这个
That's all they talk about at Erudite these days.
等等 真的有分歧者?
Wait. Divergents are real?
来吧 阿尔
Come on, Al.
第一场 彼得对特丽丝
First fight. Peter versus Tris.
什么?
What?
啊哦
Uh-oh.
埃里克干的
It's Eric.
他就是想让你名次退后
He's just trying to get back at you.
- 嘿  - 干嘛?
- Hey.  - What?
还记得我说过要怎么攻击吗?
Remember what I said about attack?
先出手一击 正中喉咙
First shot, right to the throat.
然后你看着他
And you watch him.
他出手前会先向前一步
He steps before he punches.
记住了?
All right?
嗯
Mmm.
好了吗 呆子?
All right there, stiff?
看来你要准备哭了
Look like you're about to cry.
要是你哭了 可能会考虑放点水
Might take it easy on you if you cry.
加油 特丽丝
Come on, Tris.
起来 起来
Get up. Get up.
快点 别再玩来玩去
Come on. Stop playin' with each other.
哇 你看起来...
Wow. You look...
看起来很不好
Look bad.
我躺了多久了?
How long have I been here?
差不多一天
About a day.
一天?
A day?
你看了分数板吗? 我排第几?
Have you seen the scoreboard? Where am I?
你在红线下面
You got below the line.
你们为什么穿这种背心?
Why are you wearing those vests?
战争游戏
War games.
- 哇  - 你要做什么?
- Whoa.  - What are you doing?
- 我现在就去  - 不行
- I'm coming.  - You can't.
埃里克说你的课程结束了
Eric says you're done.
什么?
What?
他说你出局了
He said you're out.
你爸爸是理事会成员 特丽丝
Your father's on the council, Tris.
也许他们会破个例 准你回家
Maybe they'll make an exception and let you go home.
我们也很难过 特丽丝
We're sorry, Tris.
我们得走了 我们要错过火车了
We gotta go. We're gonna miss the train.
好 走吧
Yeah, okay.
- 拜  - 拜
- Bye.  - Bye.
- Bye. - Bye.
谢谢
Thanks.
嗨
Hi.
- 嗨  - 你在这里做什么?
- Hi.  - What are you doing here?
我只是想着我一定要做到
I just figured that I had to make it.
谁让你出来的?
Who let you out?
我自己
I did.
你?
You did?
好
Okay.
我们坐吧
Let's sit you down.
*先夺得对方的旗帜或杀光对手者胜
游戏很简单 就像"夺旗"
The game's simple. It's like Capture the Flag.
武器是这个
Weapon of choice.
这也叫枪?
You call that a gun?
这是刺激神经的飞镖
Neuro-stim dart.
痛觉和真实的枪伤是一样的
Simulates the pain of a real gunshot wound.
只持续几分钟
Only lasts a couple minutes.
分成两队 阿四和我是队长
Two teams. Four and I are captains.
你先选
You pick first.
好 爱德华
Okay. Edward.
我选这个呆子
I'll take the stiff.
哦 选最弱的一个
Oh. Picking the weak ones
这样等你输的时候就能怪到别人身上了
so you've got someone to blame when you lose.
差不多就是这样
Something like that.
埃里克的分队去哪里了?
Where did Eric's team go?
他们肯定去到尽头了
They must have gone to the end.
好了 把灯关了
All right. Lights off.
聚在一起 快点
Gather around. Come on.
好 你的策略是什么?
Okay. What's your strategy?
我们可以把旗藏得非常严密 让他们找不到
We can hide the flag well enough so they can't find it.
我们派出一支小分队去侦查他们的位置 看看能不能找到他们的旗子
Let's send out a team to scout their location. See if we can find their flag.
我们快攻 就是...
I say we blitz them. Just...
没错 这样输得更快一点
Yeah, that's the best way to lose quickly.
让他们来找我们
Let's make them come to us.
速战速决 他们不会料到的
End this quickly, they won't expect it.
我们不知道他们在哪儿
We don't know where they are.
好 我们分成两组 防御组和进攻组
Okay, we split into two groups, defense and offense.
- 谁让你指挥了?  - 必须得有个人做决定吧
- Who put you in charge?  - Someone has to make a decision.
- 我们要更积极一点  - 我们要学聪明点
- We need to be more aggressive.  - We need to be smart about it.
你不会跳下来吧?
You're not gonna jump, are you?
不会 我只是想占领一个有利位置
No, I'm just trying to get a good vantage point.
想法不错
Good thinking.
你不必跟着我
You don't have to come with me.
你应该小心点 你刚被揍了
You should go easy. You took a beating.
我没想到你知道了
I'm surprised you noticed.
我看见你在对打的过程中走开了
I saw you leave during the fight.
没错 我不想看下去
Yeah, well, it's not something I wanted to watch.
嘿!
Hey!
你还好吗?
You good?
没事吧?
You okay?
没事 我很好
Yeah. I'm fine.
已经够高了
This is high enough.
不 我们得爬得更高一点
No, we need to go higher.
你还行吗?
You all right?
你怕高
You're afraid of heights.
每个人都有害怕的东西
Everyone's afraid of something.
我原本以为你什么都不怕
I didn't think you were afraid of anything.
不是吧 特丽丝
Come on, Tris.
你确定?
Really?
你还是人吗?
Are you even human?
也没有很难嘛
This isn't so bad.
视野不错
Good eye.
看!
Look!
在那里
There it is.
- 好了 你的计划是什么?  - 我们分成两组
- All right. What's your plan?  - We split into two groups.
我们从这边上去 剩下的人去找埃里克交战
We'll go up this side and let the rest of you engage Eric.
- 我看见他们了  - 上! 上!
- I can see 'em.  - Go! Go!
照亮他们!
Light 'em up!
还有两个! 我去接近他们!
There's two more! I'm gonna move in closer!
跟我来 上!
Follow me. Go!
- 小心右边!  - 上 上
- Watch on your right!  - Go, go, go.
上
Go.
克里斯汀娜 我们上!
Christina, let's go!
抓住他们 抓住他们!
Get 'em, get 'em!
这边走!
This way!
- 掩护我!  - 好
- Cover me!  - All right.
要是痛的话告诉我哦
Tell me if this hurts.
还是你告诉我吧
You tell me.
你个贱人!
You bitch!
混蛋
Asshole.
太棒了!
That was awesome!
掩护好!
Get covered!
上 特丽丝! 我保护你
Go, Tris! I'll guard.
哇!
Whoo!
游戏结束!
Game over!
干得好 特丽丝!
Good job, Tris!
嘿 特丽丝!
Hey, Tris!
怎么了?
Yeah?
跟我们来
Come with us.
你们去哪里?
Where you going?
走近路回去
Shortcut back.
小小的仪式 无畏派的风格
A little initiation ritual, Dauntless style.
哇
Wow.
好了 来吧!
All right, let's do this!
- 你没事吧?  - 没事
- All right, you good?  - Good.
- 系紧点  - 走你!
- Hang tight.  - Yeah. Go, go!
- 飞吧  - 哇!
- Fly, baby. - Whoo!
该你了
You're up.
快去啊!
All right, do it!
加油啊 妹子
Come on, girl.
加油! 特丽丝!
Go for it! Do it, Tris!
飞起来吧!
Like flying!
到底部别忘了拉减速带!
Don't forget to pull the brake at the bottom!
好的
Okay.
加油
Go.
准备好了吗?
You ready?
背带系好了
Harness is good.
拉减速带! 拉减速带!
Pull the brake! Pull the brake!
耶!
Yeah!
特丽丝!
Tris!
- 嘿  - 嘿
- Hey.  - Hey.
恭喜你
Congratulations.
谢谢
Thanks.
我想告诉你 今晚你表现得真棒
You know, I wanted to say that you were really good tonight.
你很勇敢
You were brave.
是的
Yeah.
好吧 你该去找你的朋友们了
Anyway, you should get back to your friends.
好吧
Okay.
如果你们的排名在红线以上
If you're ranked above the red line,
就可以进入第二阶段训练
you'll move on to the second stage of training.
如果没达到
If you're below it,
我们就不会在你身上浪费时间了
we'll waste no more time on you.
这是你们的排名
Here are your rankings.
太好了
Nice.
你做到了
You made it.
你做到了 特丽丝
You made it, Tris.
- 好了  - 谢了
- Got it.  - Thank you.
好了
Here you go.
我们通过了第一阶段训练 难道奖励就是这个吗
So we pass the first stage of training, and this is our reward.
扔上来!
Toss it up!
真有意思
Glamorous.
妈妈?
Mom?
我的女儿!
Oh, my girl!
- 妈妈 你怎么会在这里?  - 我知道他们早晚会...
- Mom, what are you doing here?  - I knew they'd assign you here...
派你来这里 瞧瞧你! 多健康漂亮
sooner or later. Look at you! God, you're so strong and beautiful.
- 妈妈 你不应该来这里  - 我知道 但你有危险
- Mom, you can't be here.  - I know, but you're in danger.
什么?
What?
我问你件事
I had to ask you something.
能力测试那天你没觉得不舒服 是吧?
You weren't sick the day you took your aptitude test, were you?
- 怎么了?  - 测试结果是什么?
- Why?  - What were your test results?
宝贝 没关系 你可以告诉我
Honey, it's okay. You can tell me.
结果是... 是不确定
They were... they were inconclusive.
你是分歧者?
Divergent?
千万别告诉别人 就连朋友和指导员都不能说
You can't tell anyone. You can't tell your friends, your instructors.
谁也不要相信
You can't trust anyone.
我没说
I'm not.
人们一直都很惧怕分歧者
People have always been so threatened by Divergents.
现在智慧派正在到处搜寻他们
But now Erudite is looking for them everywhere.
- 他们主动出击找寻他们  - 为什么?
- They're actively seeking them out.  - Why?
- 妈妈 我是什么?  - 你跟别人不同
- Mom, what am I?  - You don't conform.
你的思维方式与众不同 他们很害怕你
Your mind works in a million different ways. They're scared of you.
第二阶段的训练对你来说最危险
Stage two of training is where you are most at risk.
他们会进入你的大脑 看看你对恐惧的反应
They're gonna get inside your head and watch how you respond to fear.
你可以通过无畏派的测试的 我以前见过的
But you can pass. You can make it through Dauntless. I have seen it before.
你怎么知道的这么多关于无畏派的事?
How do you know so much about this? About Dauntless?
别管我了 千万别让他们知道你的真实身份
Never mind about me. Do not let them know who you are.
等一下! 你以前是无畏派的?
Wait! Wait! Were you Dauntless?
- 听着  - 嘿!
- Listen.  - Hey!
你在干什么?
What are you doing?
车装好了 我们走吧
Truck's loaded. Let's go.
他们对她做了什么?
What did they do to her?
特丽丝
Tris.
请坐
Take a seat.
我要给你注射一种
I'm going to inject you with a serum that stimulates
能够激发大脑恐惧的血清
the part of your brain that processes fear.
好的
Great.
它会让你产生幻觉
It induces a hallucination,
血清中的传感器能让我看到你脑中的图像
and then transmitters in the serum allow me to see the images in your mind.
- 你能看到我脑袋里的东西?  - 嗯
- You can see inside my mind?  - Mmm-hmm.
躺下
Lay back.
你马上要经历前所未有的恐惧体验 特丽丝
Now, you're gonna be facing your worst fears, Tris.
大多数人会经历十到十五钟恐惧
Most people have 10 to 15 really bad ones.
你要保持镇定
You have to calm yourself.
稳住心律和呼吸 应对你面临的情况
Slow your heart rate and your breathing, and deal with what's in front of you.
勇敢点
Be brave.
这不是真实世界
This isn't real.
没事的 没事的
It's all right, it's all right.
你还好吧?
You okay?
你觉得你在幻觉里停留了多久 特丽丝?
How long do you think you were in the hallucination, Tris?
- 二十分钟?  - 三分钟
- Twenty minutes?  - Three.
是一般人的五分之一
Four times faster than the average.
我从没见过谁第一次就做得这么好
I've never seen anyone do that well the first time.
你是怎么对付那些鸟的?
How did you get rid of the birds?
图像不是很清楚
The image wasn't clear.
呃...
Um...
我跳进水里了
I just went into the water.
第二次会容易很多
Well, next time it'll be a lot easier.
还要再做一次?
I have to do that again?
嗯 你有很多次练习机会 最后参加考试 但你天资过人
Yeah, you have to practice several times before the final, but you're a natural.
一点也不用担心
You got nothing to worry about.
我全身都爬满了小虫子
My whole body was covered in these little insects.
它们钻进我的耳朵 喉咙...
They were in my ears, and my throat...
我无法呼吸
I couldn't breathe.
我听说有个人 大约两年前...
Yeah, I heard about this guy, like two years ago...
他害怕得心脏病发作 差点死在椅子上
so panicked he had a heart attack in his chair and he almost died.
什么?
What?
我们还算幸运的 是吧?
Yeah, so we've got that to look forward to, right?
你看来一点事都没有
You didn't seem to have any problem at all.
我? 不 天啊 太可怕了
Me? No, no, my God, it was awful.
算了吧 别人的时间根本没法跟你比 你太厉害了
Oh, come on. No one even came close to your time. You were amazing.
是的 她太厉害了 会把你挤出无畏派的队伍的
Yeah, what's amazing is that she's gonna knock you right out of Dauntless.
他不会把我挤出去的
She's not gonna knock me out of Dauntless.
她从倒数第一变成了正数第一
Look, she's gone from being the worst to one of the best.
肯定有人要变成倒数第一
Somebody's gotta take her place at the bottom.
会是谁呢? 是你
Who's it gonna be? You.
你能不能别说话?
Do you ever stop talking?
我只是想知道她是怎么做到的
I just want to know how she does it.
你搞了什么把戏?
What's your trick?
什么把戏也没有
I don't have a trick.
没人能这么快结束
Nobody gets through it that fast.
你就告诉我们你怎么做到的吧?
Why don't you tell us how you do it?
至少告诉你朋友吧
At least tell your friends.
他说的什么意思?
What's he talkin' about?
- 有轻松过关的方法吗?  - 没有
- Is there some way to make it easier?  - No.
没有 我... 我什么也没做
No, I... I'm not doing anything.
嘿! 嘿!
Hey! Hey!
这不是真实世界
This isn't real.
你怎么做到的?
How'd you do that?
什么?
What?
你怎么打破玻璃的?
How'd you break the glass?
不知道 就那么打破了
I don't know. Just did it.
就那么打破了?
You just did it?
你的测试结果是什么?
What were your test results?
能力测试
Your aptitude test.
无私派
Abnegation.
我不相信
I don't think so.
什么?
What?
我觉得你在说谎
I think you're lying to me.
我为什么要说谎?
Why would I lie to you?
我再问你一遍
I'm gonna ask you one more time.
你的测试结果是什么?
What were your test results?
无私派
Abnegation.
你可以走了
Time for you to go.
特丽丝?
Tris?
告诉你吧
Just so you know,
无畏派不是那样打破玻璃的
Dauntless don't break the glass like that.
我弟弟和你一样
My brother was like you.
很快通过了第二阶段测试
During the second stage, he got good really fast.
仿真测试的最后一天
Last day of the simulations,
一个无畏派的领导来看他
one of the Dauntless leaders came to watch him.
然后第二天早上 他的尸体在峡谷里被人发现了
Then the next morning, we found his body at the bottom of the chasm.
他们杀了他
They got rid of him.
谁干的?
Who did?
无畏派的领导层
Dauntless leadership.
你不能让他们发现你
You can't let them find out about you.
如果他们已经知道了呢?
And what if they already know?
那你早没命了
Then you're already dead.
比阿特丽斯
Beatrice.
你来这里做什么?
What are you doing here?
我遇到麻烦了
I'm in trouble.
怎么了?
What happened?
我通过不了无畏派的测试
I'm not gonna make it at Dauntless.
我在那里待不下去
I don't fit in there.
你必须待下去
You have to fit in there.
我做不到
I can't.
我... 我和他们不一样
I'm just... I'm not like them.
谁和他们一样? 他们是疯子
I mean, who is? They're crazy.
或许我可以回到无私派
Maybe I can go back to Abnegation.
- 不行  - 我知道 但...
- You can't go back.  - I know, but...
他们不会让你这么做的
They're never gonna let you do that.
- 谁?  - 智慧派
- Who? - Erudite.
他们不会再让无私派打破规矩的
They're not gonna let Abnegation break any more rules.
他们真以为政府是他们说了算的吗?
They actually think that they're running the government now?
马上就是了
They might be soon.
真的吗?
Wait. Really?
智慧派应该掌权 而不是无私派
Erudite should be in charge. Certainly not Abnegation.
等一下 伽勒 你怎么会这么说?
Wait, hold on, Caleb. How can you say that?
无私派已经输了 所有人都希望那样
It's what all the other factions want, now that Abnegation failed.
不 你在这里被洗脑了...
No. That's just what they're telling you here...
- 就是那样的  - 不是
- It's true.  - It's not true.
不是那样的
It's not.
他们是在骗你
There are liars here.
那些人想要操控你
There are people who know how to manipulate you.
你一定要清醒
You need to understand that.
比阿特丽斯
Beatrice.
我想你该走了
I think you should go.
派别比亲情重要 是吧?
Faction before blood. Yeah?
我懂了
Got it.
你需要跟我走
I need you to come with me.
住手!
Stop!
你没事吧?
Are you all right?
我没事
Yeah, I'm fine.
请坐
Please, sit down.
谢谢
Thank you.
我很高兴你今天来了
I'm glad you came here today.
是吗?
You are?
你在新派别里过得好吗?
Are you happy with your new faction?
嗯
Yeah.
但你过来找你哥哥了
But you came to see your brother.
我... 我只是想和他聊聊
I just... I just wanted to talk to him.
你见过你的父母吗?
Have you seen your parents?
没有
No.
很难接受吧
It's hard to let go.
派别比亲情重要
Faction before blood.
说起来容易
It's an important ideal,
做起来却很难
but sometimes difficult to fulfill.
这与我们的人性有冲突
It goes against our fundamental human nature.
但人性正是我们需要
But that's exactly the weakness
克服的弱点
we need to overcome.
你觉得人性是弱点?
You think that human nature is a weakness?
我觉得人性是敌人
I think human nature is the enemy.
人性让我们有秘密 撒谎 偷盗
It's human nature to keep secrets, lie, steal.
我想要消除这些
And I wanna eradicate that.
这样社会才能永保安定和平
That's how we'll maintain a stable, peaceful society.
你会帮我的 是吧?
You would help me with that, wouldn't you?
我怎么帮你?
How would I help you?
你知道无私派正在破坏派别系统
You're aware that Abnegation is undermining
还违反法律
the faction system and breaking laws
窝藏分歧者吧?
harboring Divergents?
我不知道
I didn't know that.
如果真是那样 我很高兴我离开了
But if that's true, then I'm glad that I left.
你要向我保证
See, I need to know that I can count on you
你能够遵守法律
to enforce the law,
即便触犯法律的人是跟你亲近的人
even if it's been broken by someone close to you.
是你很在乎的人
Someone you care about.
没问题
Of course.
很好
Good.
那我就让我的车把你送回无畏派
Then I'll have my car take you back to Dauntless.
快啊! 搞定她!
Come on! Get her over!
快点 推下去! 推下去!
Come on, do it! Do it!
嘿!
Hey!
你还好吧?
You all right?
还好
Yeah.
来吧 我们走
Come on. Let's go.
给你 穿上这个
Here, put this on.
谢谢
Thank you.
你在这儿会很安全
You'll be safe here.
抱歉
Sorry.
没事
It's okay.
我无法相信阿尔...
I can't believe Al...
你的排名在上升 他在下降
You're moving up through the ranks, and he's failing.
这会让他恨自己 也会恨你
It makes him hate himself and it makes him hate you.
他只是害怕
He's just afraid.
每个人都害怕
Everyone's afraid.
我知道 但是恐惧对阿尔这样的人会有奇怪的效果
I know, but fear does something strange to people like Al.
对你则不会
But not you.
恐惧不会让你放弃 却会唤醒你
Fear doesn't shut you down, it wakes you up.
我见过的
I've seen it.
你应该躺下
You should lie down.
- 睡一会儿  - 好
- Get some sleep.  - Yeah.
我在地板上睡
I'll take the floor.
感觉怎么样了?
How you feeling?
好多了
Better.
很好
Good.
昨天你去了哪里?
Where'd you go yesterday?
去见我哥哥
To see my brother.
你在这儿感觉有点无聊 对吗?
It's getting a little boring for you here, is it?
我哥哥说...
My brother said that...
他认为智慧派正计划推翻无私派的掌权
He thinks Erudite is planning to overthrow Abnegation.
你觉得他们能做到吗?
Do you think they could do that?
我觉得能 很有可能
Yeah, I do. I think it's possible.
取决于他们想以什么代价达到目的
Depends how far they're willing to go.
我很担心爸爸妈妈
I'm worried about my parents.
是啊
Yeah.
但我觉得你还有其他应该担心的事情
But I think you got other things you need to worry about.
不是吗?
Don't you?
是的
Yeah.
我该走了
I should go.
嗨
Hi.
嘿
Hey.
这是你的毛衫吗?
Is that your sweater?
不是
No.
那么昨晚发生了什么?
So what happened to you last night?
特丽丝 我能跟你说句话吗?
Tris, can I talk to you for a second?
听着 我只想说我很抱歉
Listen, I just wanted to say that I'm sorry.
我不知道自己是怎么想的
I don't know what's wrong with me.
求你了 能原谅我吗?
Please, can you ever forgive me?
如果你再敢靠近我 我会杀了你
If you ever come close to me again, I will kill you.
特丽丝...
Tris...
离我远点!
You need to stay away from me!
你这个懦夫
You are a coward.
我简直不相信他会那么做
I just can't believe he would do that.
一点都不像他的为人
It's not like him at all.
那边怎么了?
What's that?
使劲儿
Come on.
天啊!
Oh, my God!
好像是刚刚跳下去的
Guess he just jumped.
特丽丝
Tris.
特丽丝!
Tris!
让我一个人静一静
Leave me alone.
我对阿尔的事感到很遗憾
I'm sorry about Al.
他的死是我的错
It's my fault that he's dead.
不 跟你无关 那是他自己的选择
No, it's not because of you. He made his own choice.
否则他就会无家可归
He would have been factionless.
他肯定不会通过最后的测试
He was not gonna pass that final test.
我也不会
Neither am I.
为什么那么说?
Why do you say that?
你知道原因的
You know why.
只要其他人发现 他们就会杀了我
And as soon as all the others find out, they're gonna kill me.
我不会让那一幕发生
I'm not gonna let that happen.
关上门
Shut the door.
你需要练习
You're gonna practice.
- 在我感到恐惧的情形下?  - 不是
- In my fear landscape?  - No.
在我这里
In mine.
我们一起练习
We go in together.
你以前这么做过吗?
Have you ever done this before?
没有 从未做过
No, I haven't.
你确定要这样吗?
You sure you want to?
为什么不呢?
Why wouldn't I?
我不知道 你从未对我讲过你的任何事
I don't know. You haven't told me anything about yourself
然后现在就要让我进入你的大脑?
and now you're just gonna let me inside of your head?
- 你害怕吗?  - 你不害怕吗?
- Are you afraid of that?  - You're not?
不会
No.
恐高
Fear of heights.
我一点都不吃惊
I'm not surprised.
这不是真的
It's not real.
- 不  - 我们可以跳下去
- No.  - We could just jump.
分歧者才会跳下去
Divergent would jump.
无畏派会去那边的高楼
Dauntless would get to that building.
如果你想通过 如果你想不被发现
If you want to pass, if you want to avoid discovery,
你必须按照无畏派的方式去做
you have to do everything the way a Dauntless would do it.
找一些工具 想办法幸存下来
You have to find some tool, some method to survive.
害怕被囚禁
Fear of confinement.
你得想办法解决 无畏派的人会怎么做?
You have to find a way of stopping it. What would a Dauntless do?
很好!
Good!
慢慢来
Take your time.
我开始有点享受在这个缩小的盒子了
I'm just enjoying myself in this shrinking box.
作为一个无畏派的战士 你必须服从命令 尽管你并不赞同
As a Dauntless soldier, you have to follow orders you don't always agree with.
她是谁?
Who is she?
她是无辜的
She's an innocent.
我必须杀了她
I have to kill her.
但这样我下不去手
But I can never do it.
除非看着别处
Unless I look away.
我们为什么在无私派这里?
Why are we in Abnegation?
最后的恐惧会最可怕
Your last fear is your worst fear.
它深居于灵魂深处
It lives in the deepest part of your mind.
马库斯曾经有个儿子
Marcus had a son.
叫什么名字?
What was his name?
托拜厄斯
Tobias.
托拜厄斯...
Tobias...
我只想帮助你 让你更好一些
I'm just trying to help you to be better.
不!
No!
阿四?
Four?
有四怕?
Four fears?
以前是 现在也是
Four then, four now.
我总是去那里 但我觉得永远不会消失的
I keep going in there, but I don't think you ever lose them.
我能问你一件事吗?
Can I ask you something?
当然
Sure.
你的纹身是什么?
What's your tattoo?
想看看吗?
You wanna see it?
了不起
It's amazing.
所有的派别
The factions.
为什么把它们都纹在身上?
Why do you have all of them?
我不想要只是某一派
I don't want to be just one thing.
也做不到
I can't be.
我想要勇敢 无私...
I want to be brave and I want to be selfless...
智慧 诚实和仁慈
Intelligent and honest and kind.
尽管我仍在努力做到仁慈
Although I'm still working on "kind."
我不想进展得太快
I don't wanna go too fast.
没关系
It's okay.
我已经习惯睡在地板上了
I've already got my spot on the floor.
早上好
Morning.
嘿
Hey.
来 我给你看点东西
Come on. I'm gonna show you something.
好的
Okay.
看
Look.
- 是智慧派  - 没错
- Erudite.  - Yeah.
每天早上他们都在这里
They're here every morning.
我观察他们好几个星期了
I've been watching them for weeks.
他们在无畏派做什么?
What are they doing at Dauntless?
装载补给 计算机
Loading in supplies. Computers.
还有这个
And these.
这是什么?
What is it?
我觉得是某种认知发射剂 像血清一样注射
I think it's some kind of cognitive transmitter. You inject it like a serum.
为什么?
Why?
应该会让人更容易被控制
It's supposed to make you more susceptible to suggestion,
但他们这么多的量 完全可以组建一支军队
but as many as they have, they could create an army.
注意 所有新成员报到参加最后的测试
Attention, all initiates report for final testing.
所有新成员报到参加最后的测试
All initiates report for final testing.
你准备好了
You're ready.
你可以做到
You can do this.
他们能在屏幕上看到你的幻觉
They can see your hallucinations on the screen.
所有你得按照无畏派的方式应对恐惧
So you get past your fears the way a Dauntless would,
但是要快
but do it quickly.
没错 如果我太优秀 他们会杀了我 如果太慢 我会死掉
Right. If I'm too good, then they'll kill me, and if I'm too slow, then I'll die.
对
Right.
祝你好运
Good luck.
祝你好运 特丽丝
Good luck, Tris.
希望你能做到
Hope you make it.
祝贺你
Congratulations.
哇哦 阿四!
Whoa. Four!
住手! 阿四!
Stop! Four!
你不是无畏派的吗?
Aren't you Dauntless?
别告诉我刚才你也都看到了
Please tell me that you weren't watching that.
如果我说不 你会觉得好些吗?
Would you feel better if I said no?
做得很好
You did well.
现在...
Now...
最后一个测试
One final test.
你知道应该怎么做
You know what to do.
什么?
What?
如果你想加入无畏派
If you want to be Dauntless.
不
No.
下手吧
Do it.
你还好吗?
You all right?
我觉得你做得不错 好吗?
That looked good to me, okay?
来吧 我们走
Come on. Let's go.
祝贺你
Congratulations,
无畏派的新成员
new members of Dauntless.
无畏派! 无畏派! 无畏派!
Dauntless! Dauntless! Dauntless!
快点 排好队
Come on. Get in line.
好了 各位 排好
All right, everybody, line up.
发生什么了?
What's going on?
所有无畏派的新成员
All Dauntless initiates,
去你们的指挥官那里报到
report to your command leader.
好了 都听着!
All right, listen up!
在你们今晚离开之前 我要你们排成四列
Before you leave tonight, I want you all in four lines.
每个人会得到一个追踪设备
Everyone gets a tracking device.
不要问问题 只是以防万一
Don't ask questions. It's just a precaution.
看见阿四了吗?
Do you see Four?
没有
No.
下一个!
Next!
- 发生什么了?  - 天啊
- What's going on?  - Oh, my God.
祝贺你
Congratulations.
你应该站在队首的 但是...
You should be first in line, but...
我来给你帮个忙
I'll make it easy for you.
很疼吧 哈?
Hurts like a bitch, huh?
现在你真正是我们的一员了
Now you're really one of us.
嘿 怎么了...
Hey, what's...
派别比亲情重要
Faction before blood.
天啊
Oh, my God.
他们能听见 也能看见我们
They can see and hear us.
只是不会像正常人一样做出反应
They just don't process it the same way.
命令通过发射器下达
Commands come in through the transmitter.
发生什么了?
What's goin' on?
我们在干什么?
What are we doin'?
是个分歧者
Divergent.
嘿! 一切正常 没什么需要担心的
Hey! Everything's fine. There's nothing to worry about.
快点! 出来!
Hurry up! Move!
无私派的领袖必须出示身份证明
Abnegation leaders must identify themselves.
我们得找到我的父母
We need to find my parents.
继续走 你家在哪?
Just keep moving. Where's your house?
我们在找寻机密
We are looking for information.
所有房屋都要搜查
All houses will be searched.
不要反抗 不会伤害你们的
Do not resist. You will not be hurt.
妈妈? 爸爸?
Mom? Dad?
他们会去哪呢?
Where would they have gone?
不知道
I don't know.
你们不能这样! 快住手!
This can't happen here! Just stop it!
不要反抗
Do not resist.
所有无私派的人都要受审讯
All Abnegation will be questioned.
传说中的阿四... 变成了无脑的机器
The legendary Four... A mindless drone.
你曾经是班上第一 而现在...
You were first in your class. Now you're...
一无是处
Nothing.
怎么?
What?
你觉得他可能是...
Think he might be...
只有一个办法可以知道
There's one way to find out.
- 道别吧 混蛋  - 再见
- Say goodbye, asshole. - Goodbye.
动一下就打死你!
Move and you die!
呆子?
The stiff?
两个呆子
Two stiffs.
两个要死的呆子
Two dead stiffs.
一个分歧者也不能放过
You can't let a single Divergent slip through.
- 还真是没错  - 她不会开枪的
- This is what happens. - She's not gonna shoot me.
你可能高估我的善心了
Think you might be overestimating my character.
快跑!
Run!
- 你中枪了?  - 嗯
- You were hit?  - Yeah.
就在这! 不许动!
Right there! Don't move!
放心武器
Drop your weapons.
是托拜厄斯·伊顿
Tobias Eaton.
还有你 比阿特丽斯
And you, Beatrice.
我以为在你身上觉察到的是智慧
I thought it was intellect I was sensing in you.
或许你没有自以为的那么聪明
Maybe you're not as smart as you think you are.
你为什么要攻击这些无辜的人?
Why are you attacking all these innocent people?
无辜的人?
Innocent people?
如果不加以管制 无私派就会破坏派别系统
Abnegation, if left unchecked, will destroy the faction system.
你们两个也是
Same can be said of both of you.
必须有人阻止你们 否则和平就要被打破
Somebody has to stop you. If we don't, peace will be lost.
和平已经打破了 是你破坏的
It's already been lost. You destroyed it.
是人性破坏的
Human nature destroyed it.
我们这些有能力预见的人有责任保护其它人
Those of us with the vision to see that are called upon to protect the rest.
我们会恢复和平 而这次会一直持续下去
We will restore the peace. And this time, it will last.
如果你错了呢?
And what if you're wrong?
把他带过来
Bring him with us.
她受伤了 任何结果都会失真
She's injured. Any results would be unclear.
- 可以处理掉她了  - 好的
- You can get rid of her. - All right.
跪下!
Get down!
我们走 快!
Let's go. Come on!
刚到的安保队 到五级移动司令部报到
Additional security teams, report to mobile command Level 5.
比阿特丽斯!
Beatrice!
- 妈妈? 妈!  - 比阿特丽斯
- Mom? Mom!  - Beatrice.
好了
Okay.
好 我们得赶紧跑!
Okay, we gotta run!
您曾经是无畏派的
You were Dauntless.
今天派上用场了
Served me well today.
爸爸没事吧?
Is Dad okay?
嗯 他带着一队人去了门罗州 我们在那儿汇合
Yeah. He led a group over to Monroe and State. We're gonna meet him there.
快走!
Let's go!
发现目标!
Copy 1-9!
威尔! 威尔!
Will! Will!
威尔! 威尔 住手! 住手!
Will! Will, stop! Stop!
快住手!
Stop!
我...
I...
好了 快 宝贝 我们得走了
Okay. Come on, honey. We gotta go.
我杀了他 我杀了他 是我杀了他
I killed him. I killed him. I killed him.
过来
Come here.
好了
Okay.
我们去找你父亲
Let's go find your father.
- 掩护我  - 不
- Cover me.  - No.
我先走
I'll go.
发现目标 长官!
Got it, sir!
别停下! 别停!
Don't stop! Don't stop!
快走!
Go!
- 你没事吧?  - 嗯 没事 挺好的
- You okay?  - Yeah, good. I'm good.
好! 我们走! 安全了
Okay! Let's go! We're good.
妈妈?
Mom?
妈... 怎么了?
Mom... What is it?
嘿...
Hey...
妈!妈! 妈妈!
Mom! Mom! Mom!
妈妈! 妈 不要!
Mom! Mom, no!
妈妈! 妈妈!
Mom! Mom!
妈? 妈妈! 醒来啊!
Mom? Mom! Mom, wake up!
妈!
Mom!
天啊 妈妈!
Oh, my God, Mom!
住手! 住手!
Stop! Stop!
我爱你 妈妈...
I love you, Mom...
天啊!
Oh, my God!
我父亲呢?
Where's my father?
比阿特丽斯?
Beatrice?
你妈妈呢?
Your mother?
她救了我
She saved me.
她为了救我死的
那她没有白白牺牲
Then it wasn't in vain.
我们得离开这里
We need to leave here.
外面有士兵吗?
Are there soldiers outside?
没有 安全的
No, it's clear.
我应该相信你的
I should have believed you.
我一意识到问题就离开了
I left as soon as I realized.
为什么会这样? 我不明白
Why is this happening? I don't understand.
无畏派为什么要给智慧派卖命?
Why are Dauntless fighting for Erudite?
他们不知道自己在干嘛
They don't know what they're doing.
他们被控制了
They're under simulation.
我们得唤醒他们 我得进入无畏派内部
We need to wake 'em up. I need to get into Dauntless.
那是座堡垒
That's a fortress.
不可能成功的
It's not gonna happen.
我可以带你们进去
I can get us in there.
准备好
Get ready.
又要干嘛?
What now?
你不会喜欢的
You're not gonna like it.
这个下面有张网
There's a net at the bottom.
别多想 只管跳
Don't think, just jump.
没事吧?
Are you good?
都没事吧?
Good?
我们走
Let's go.
等一下
Wait here.
趴到墙上
Against the wall.
趴墙上!
Against the wall!
你怎么是清醒的?
How are you awake?
因为我比你聪明
Because I'm smarter than you.
而他们需要我
And they need me.
控制中心在哪里?
Where are they controlling it from?
我为什么要告诉你? 反正你又不会开枪的
Why would I tell you that? It's not like you're gonna shoot me.
为什么你们都这么说?
Why do people keep saying that?
控制中心在哪里?
Where are they controlling it from?
你非得开枪打他吗?
Did you really need to shoot him?
每浪费一分钟 就会有无私派的人死去
Every minute we waste, another Abnegation dies
无畏派的人变成凶手
and another Dauntless becomes a murderer.
彼得 我们走
Peter, let's go.
是这儿 对不对?
That's it, isn't it?
对
Yeah.
我见过珍宁进去
I've seen Jeanine go in there.
她就是在这儿控制大家的
That's where she's controlling it from.
如你所说 一秒钟也不能浪费
Like you said, there isn't a second to waste.
爸爸 不!
Dad, no!
爸爸...
Dad...
不惜一切代价...
Do whatever it takes...
嘿!
Hey!
看着伽勒 我先进去
Watch Caleb. I'm going in there.
嘿 嗨
Hey. Hi.
阿四...
Four...
阿四... 阿四 是我 你被控制了
Four... Four, it's me. You're in a SIM.
他听不到你说话
He can't hear you.
很神奇 对吧?
Amazing, isn't it?
我们以为称之为人的一切
Everything we think of that makes up a person,
思想 感情 过往...
thoughts, emotions, history...
都被化学物抹掉了
All wiped away by chemistry.
阿四
Four.
他已经不是他自己了
He's gone.
这样我们更安全
And we're all safer for it.
更安全? 怎么就更安全了?
Safer? How are we safer?
派别体系的天才之处
The brilliance of the faction system
就是对派别的服从会把
is that conformity to the faction removes the threat
能行驶自由意志的人构成的威胁消除
of anyone exercising their independent will.
分歧者威胁到了这种体系
Divergents threaten that system.
别误会
Don't get me wrong.
你的反抗和拒绝被归类
There's a certain beauty in your resistance,
有些许美感
your defiance of categorization.
但这是我们无法承受的美
But it's a beauty we can't afford.
阿四 是我 是我
Four, it's me. It's me.
拜托 阿四 看着我 看着我
Please, Four, look at me. Look at me.
阿四! 是我啊!
Four! It's me!
阿四 住手!
Four, stop!
停下!
Stop!
停下...
Stop...
阿四... 求你...
Four... Please...
没事的 没事的 我爱你 没关系
It's okay, it's okay. I love you. It's okay.
没关系
It's okay.
我爱你 没事的
I love you. It's okay.
阿四 看着我 看着我
Four, look at me. Look at me.
是我 是我
It's me. It's me.
是我 是我啊
特丽丝...
Tris...
动手吧
Go.
迅速搞定
Finish it.
救命!
Help!
嘿!
Hey!
关闭系统
Shut it down.
不
No.
我不会再说第二遍 快点!
I am not gonna ask you again. Do it!
关闭系统!
Shut it down!
我很敬佩你甘愿为信仰牺牲...
I admire you willing to die for what you believe...
但我也一样
but so am I.
你下不了手 对吧?
You can't do it, can you?
或许你没有自己想得那么无畏
Maybe you're not quite as Dauntless as you thought you were.
你说得对
You're right.
我没有
I'm not.
因为我是分歧者
I'm Divergent.
现在关闭系统清除程序
Now shut it down and wipe the program.
控制终止
Simulation abort.
系统全面关闭
System-wide shutdown.
不... 不...
No... No...
不!
No!
别误会
Don't get me wrong.
你的反抗还有些许美感
There's a certain beauty to your resistance.
特丽丝...
Tris...
现在一级封锁启动
Lockdown now in effect.
好了 快走!
All right, let's move!
我们得走了 立刻
We gotta go. Now.
托拜厄斯
Tobias.
我们得继续走
We need to keep moving.
好 快走!
All right, move!
儿子!
Son!
我能行!
I got it!
我知道
I know you do.
我爸妈今天都死了
My mom and dad died today.
他们走了
They're gone.
我知道
I know.
但他们爱你 特丽丝
But they loved you, Tris.
对他们来说 这是最好的证明方法
For them, there was no better way to show you.
现在我们什么都没了
Now we have nothing.
我们没有家 没有派别...
We have no home, no faction...
我都不知道自己是谁了
I don't even know who I am anymore.
我很清楚你是谁
I know exactly who you are.
你确定吗?
You sure about that?
对 非常确定
Yeah, I'm very sure.
过来
Come here.
我们现在和无派别的人一样了
We're like the Factionless now.
我们把一切都抛下了
We've left everything behind,
但我们找到了自我和彼此
but we found ourselves and each other.
明日我们或许还要战斗
Tomorrow we may have to fight again,
但现在 我们会坐着火车到终点...
but, for now, we'll ride the train to the end of the line...
然后纵身一跃
and then we'll jump.